<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="WordPress/2.8.4" -->
<rss version="0.92">
<channel>
	<title>John Culberson - U.S. House of Representatives</title>
	<link>http://culberson.house.gov</link>
	<description>culberson.house.gov - District 7 - Houston, TX</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 18:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
	<language>en</language>
	
	<item>
		<title>Culberson Statement on The REAL Space Act</title>
		<description>I co-sponsored the RE-asserting American Leadership in Space Act (The REAL Space Act) again this Congress because I believe it is critical for NASA to have a bold vision for space exploration, one that the President has failed to provide.

Johnson Space Center would flourish with a declared mission to return ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/culberson-statement-on-the-real-space-act/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>President Obama&#8217;s Budget: More of the Same Failed Policies</title>
		<description>The President’s Budget By The Numbers
 


	$8.2 Trillion In New Debt
	$1.1 Trillion In New Taxes
	$964 Billion In New Spending

The budget President Obama finally released today is months late and so full of gimmicks that the President cannot claim he is supporting deficit reduction. The fact is President Obama’s budget will ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/president-obamas-budget-more-of-the-same-failed-policies/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Voting Record</title>
		<description>






Roll Call Votes

 A roll call vote records how each Member of the House voted, but many votes are cast by voice-vote for which there is no official record of a Member's position.  To learn more about compiling a Member's voting record, visit the Library of Congress'a website by ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/voting-record/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Congressman John Culberson (TX-7) Wins FRC Action’s ‘True Blue’ Award for Unwavering Support of the Family</title>
		<description>WASHINGTON, D.C. – FRC Action and CitizenLink recognized Congressman John Culberson (TX-7) as a “True Blue” Member of Congress for unwavering commitment and consistent support in defense of life and the family. Rep. Culberson was one of only 89 current representatives and 4 current senators to score a perfect 100 ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/congressman-john-culberson-tx-7-wins-frc-action%e2%80%99s-%e2%80%98true-blue%e2%80%99-award-for-unwavering-support-of-the-family/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Energy Independence: Now is the Time</title>
		<description>The Keystone XL pipeline project is not just a pipeline – it’s a lifeline. It’s a lifeline for the tens of thousands of out-of-work Americans who will gain direct jobs from its construction and implementation, and it’s a lifeline for the millions of Americans who feel the pain of rising ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/energy-independence-now-is-the-time/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Culberson Opposes the President&#8217;s Decision to Close the White House to the Public</title>
		<description>Rep. John Culberson joined other Members of Congress in writing a letter to President Obama protesting the White House’s decision to cancel public tours. On March 5, 2013, the White House abruptly announced that they were canceling all tours “until further notice.” This decision comes as thousands of students and ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/culberson-opposes-the-presidents-decision-to-close-the-white-house-to-the-public/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Truth About Obamacare and the Continuing Resolution (CR)</title>
		<description>


	There is no new Obamacare funding in the CR.


	There is no dedicated funding stream for Obamacare in the CR.


Yesterday I voted for the H.R. 933, the Department of Defense, Military Construction and Veterans Affairs, and Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act of 2013. The bill provides our military and veterans with the ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/the-truth-about-obamacare-and-the-continuing-resolution-cr/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Rep. Culberson Discusses our Federal Spending Problem</title>
		<description>  </description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/rep-culberson-discusses-our-federal-spending-problem/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Supporting Our Veterans</title>
		<description>One of the best parts of my job is supporting our men and women in  uniform, from nominating outstanding high school students to our  military academies to ensuring rights and protections for our veterans.  Yesterday, I chaired a hearing of the Military Construction and Veterans  Affairs ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/supporting-our-veterans/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Rep. Culberson to Chair Hearing with Joint Chiefs of Staff</title>
		<description>I’m honored to chair the first hearing of the Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Subcommittee this morning with the Joint Chiefs of Staff. The hearing will focus on military force structure and construction projects, and will give Congress a clear picture of the military’s ability to face developing global ...</description>
		<link>http://culberson.house.gov/rep-culberson-to-chair-hearing-with-joint-chiefs-of-staff/</link>
			</item>
</channel>
</rss>
