<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ruiz.house.gov/rss.xml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Congressman  Raul Ruiz - Representing the 36th District of California</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/rss.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
          <item>
    <title>Dr. Ruiz Highlights First 100 Days in Congress</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-highlights-first-100-days-in-congress</link>
    <description>&amp;nbsp;Washington, DC&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; Last Friday marked the first 100 days in Congress for Dr. Raul Ruiz (D-Palm Desert). Since being sworn into office on January 3, 2013, Dr. Ruiz has:Helped 124 constituents resolve their caseworkOpened two district officesDelivered two speeches on the House floorIntroduced legislation to provide incentives for global companies and investors to create jobs in the 36th&amp;nbsp;District and throughout the United States [H.R. 1413]Voted to block a Congressional pay raise [H.R. 273]Voted for the bipartisan &amp;ldquo;No Budget, No Pay&amp;rdquo; Act to&amp;nbsp;withhold&amp;nbsp;Congressional pay if Congress fails to pass a budget&amp;nbsp;[H.R. 325]Voted with House Republicans to pass a bill requiring the President to submit a proposal to balance the federal budget [H.R. 444]Voted for the bipartisan Violence Against Women Act to strengthen the ability of the federal government, states, and law enforcement agencies to combat sexual assault and domestic abuse [S. 47]Voted for bipartisan legislation to create jobs and cut red tape for the development of clean hydropower energy&amp;nbsp;[H.R. 254]Voted against the Ryan Budget which ends the Medicare guarantee [H. Con. Res. 25] and spoke out against the President&amp;rsquo;s proposed cuts to Medicare and Social SecurityVoted to ensure that tribal communities receive equitable treatment during&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;natural disaster [H.R. 219] and voted to ensure that Native American women who are victims of sexual or domestic abuse have equal access to justice [S. 47]Cosponsored bipartisan legislation to make higher education more affordable for veterans [H.R. 357] and bipartisan legislation to help disabled veterans receive full benefits [H.R. 333]Joined 212 Members of Congress in filing an amicus brief in the United States Supreme Court opposing the Defense of Marriage Act (DOMA)Worked with Senator Boxer (D-CA) and the Army Corps of Engineers to secure a $200,000 request to advance a state plan to create a 3,770-acre complex of shallow ponds near the Salton Sea as part of a longer-term restoration effortProvided free medical care to local residents during the Remote Area Medical (RAM) Health Expedition in IndioJoined a bipartisan group of Members of Congress in urging the Postmaster General to continue delivering prescription medications to seniors and veterans in light of the proposed 5-day delivery scheduleParticipated in many local community events including: the Beaumont Veterans&amp;rsquo; Expo, the Palm Springs Black History parade, the Riverside County Date Festival Parade, the Desert Hot Springs Health clinic grant opening, the Palm Springs Chamber Lunch, the La Quinta Chamber Lunch, the Desert Hot Springs Chamber lunch, the Coachella Valley Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Walk, the BNP Paribas Open Salute to Heroes, the Rainbow Youth Summit, the LGBT Marriage Equality Rally, the James O. Jesse Highland Unity Center Community Block Grant Celebration, and the San Jacinto First People&amp;rsquo;s Day Parade and Festival###</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, April 15, 2013 - 2:23pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-highlights-first-100-days-in-congress%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Dr. Ruiz Statement on Cuts to Medicare and Social Security in the President’s Budget</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-statement-on-cuts-to-medicare-and-social-security-in-the</link>
    <description>&amp;nbsp;Washington, DC&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; Today Dr. Raul Ruiz (D-Palm Desert) released the following statement on the proposed cuts to Medicare and Social Security included in the President&amp;rsquo;s budget:&amp;ldquo;I was disappointed that the President&amp;rsquo;s budget released today included cuts to Medicare and Social Security. Putting the burden of the national deficit on the backs of our seniors is wrong, and I will stand with our seniors to oppose any effort from either political party that would cut their hard-earned benefits and force them to pay even more out-of-pocket for health care. At a time when many seniors are barely making ends meet, we should be working in a bipartisan way to responsibly reduce the deficit and strengthen Medicare and Social Security, and I am committed to working with both political parties toward that end.&amp;rdquo;###</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, April 10, 2013 - 5:55pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-statement-on-cuts-to-medicare-and-social-security-in-the%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Dr. Ruiz Introduces First Bill, the SelectUSA Authorization Act of 2013</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-introduces-first-bill-the-selectusa-authorization-act-of-2013</link>
    <description>Washington, DC&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; Today Dr. Raul Ruiz (D-Palm Desert) introduced his first bill, the SelectUSA Authorization Act of 2013. This legislation, which is part of the &amp;ldquo;Make it in America&amp;rdquo; plan in the U.S. House of Representatives, will authorize the SelectUSA initiative and provide incentives for global companies and investors to create jobs in the United States.&amp;ldquo;America should be the premier place in the world to do business, and this bill will help increase our competitiveness in the global economy by recruiting international companies to our shores and providing incentives for investors to create high-quality jobs here at home,&amp;rdquo; said Dr. Ruiz. &amp;ldquo;There are people all across the 36th&amp;nbsp;District who are ready to get to work.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;By attracting global businesses to our local communities, this common sense legislation will help create well-paying jobs and strengthen our economy locally and throughout the country.&amp;quot;The SelectUSA initiative is the first federal initiative focused on attracting, retaining, and expanding global business investment and development in the United States. SelectUSA serves as a one-stop shop for investors and businesses that want to create jobs in the United States. The initiative helps link local communities with international companies and investors who want to expand to the United States.Dr. Ruiz&amp;rsquo;s bill also includes accountability and transparency measures to ensure adequate oversight of the SelectUSA initiative.###</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, April 9, 2013 - 4:04pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-introduces-first-bill-the-selectusa-authorization-act-of-2013%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Dr. Ruiz Announces 2013 Congressional Art Competition</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-announces-2013-congressional-art-competition</link>
    <description>&amp;nbsp;WASHINGTON, DC&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;--&amp;nbsp;The office of Dr. Raul Ruiz (D-Palm Desert) is now accepting submissions for the 2013 Congressional Art Competition.Each spring, Members of the U.S. House of Representatives sponsor a nationwide high school arts competition to recognize the artistic talents of their young constituents. Since 1982, more than 650,000 high school students have participated in the competition.&amp;ldquo;The 36th&amp;nbsp;District is home to some of the most talented artists in the nation, and the Congressional Art Competition provides our local student artists with a unique opportunity to showcase their creativity on a national stage,&amp;rdquo; said Dr. Ruiz. &amp;ldquo;I look forward to reviewing the submissions and encourage all interested high school students to participate in this year&amp;rsquo;s competition.&amp;rdquo;The Artistic Discovery Contest is open to high school students who are residents of the 36th District. Public, private and home-schooled students are invited and encouraged to participate. The winning submission will be displayed for one year in the U.S. Capitol. The exhibit in Washington will also include artwork from other contest winners nationwide.&amp;nbsp;Art works entered in the contest may be 28&amp;quot; x 28&amp;quot; x 4&amp;quot;, inlucing the frame. All entries should be original in concept, design, and execution. &amp;nbsp;The artwork may be:&amp;middot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Paintings, including oil, acrylics, and watercolor&amp;middot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Drawings, including pastels, colored pencil, pencil, charcoal, ink, and markers&amp;middot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Prints, including lithographs, silkscreen, and block prints&amp;middot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Mixed Media&amp;middot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Computer generated art&amp;middot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PhotographyThe artist and his or her family will be invited to a reception at the U.S. Capitol along with the winners from other Congressional Districts across the country.&amp;nbsp;Visit&amp;nbsp;https://ruiz.house.gov/services/art-competition&amp;nbsp;to fill out the Student Release Form and see the Guidelines for Teachers and Students.For more information, please contact Amanda Bogorad at&amp;nbsp;amanda.bogorad@mail.house.gov&amp;nbsp;or 760-424-8888.###</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, March 27, 2013 - 3:21pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-announces-2013-congressional-art-competition%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Dr. Ruiz Delivers Floor Speech in Opposition to the Ryan Budget  </title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-delivers-floor-speech-in-opposition-to-the-ryan-budget</link>
    <description>Washington, DC &amp;ndash; Dr. Raul Ruiz (D-Palm Desert) delivered remarks on the House floor today in opposition to the Fiscal Year 2014 Ryan Budget, which ends the Medicare guarantee for seniors.&amp;nbsp;Below are Dr. Ruiz&amp;rsquo;s remarks:&amp;ldquo;This Congress has a responsibility and an opportunity to work together to grow our economy and set this nation on a fiscally responsible path. However, the Ryan budget is irresponsible and places the burden of the deficit on hard-working American families and seniors. This plan ends the guarantee of Medicare.&amp;ldquo;As an ER doctor, I know that many of my senior patients are struggling financially and rely on Medicare. Our priority should be reducing healthcare costs in order to make Medicare stronger and sustainable. But this budget transforms Medicare into a voucher program, shifting the cost of health care to our seniors.&amp;ldquo;We must work together to protect and preserve Medicare, reduce our deficit, and decrease healthcare costs. I urge my colleagues to come together across party lines and put American families and our seniors first.&amp;rdquo;###</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, March 20, 2013 - 6:12pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/dr-ruiz-delivers-floor-speech-in-opposition-to-the-ryan-budget%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Rep. Ruiz Announces Opening of Hemet Office</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-announces-opening-of-hemet-office</link>
    <description>Washington, DC&amp;nbsp;--- U.S. Representative Raul Ruiz, M.D. (D-Palm Desert) today announced the opening of his district office in Hemet.The Hemet district office is located at 445 East Florida Avenue, Hemet, CA 92543.&amp;ldquo;I have said from the start that I will always put people first, and my office is committed to doing that by providing high-quality constituent services to the people of the 36th District,&amp;rdquo; said Rep. Ruiz. &amp;ldquo;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s our office in Hemet, Palm Springs, or Washington, DC, my door is always open and my staff and I are here to serve. I encourage people in Hemet to reach out to us and take advantage of the resources and services available through our new local office.&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;We are both pleased and proud to have Congressman Ruiz&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;Hemet office located in Hemet&amp;#39;s City Hall,&amp;rdquo; said Hemet Mayor Robert Youssef. &amp;ldquo;This convenient location will&amp;nbsp;provide all of Hemet&amp;#39;s citizens easy access to the Congressman&amp;#39;s staff.&amp;rdquo;Rep. Ruiz also has a district office located at&amp;nbsp;777 East Tahquitz Canyon Way, Palm Springs, CA, 92262.###</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, March 14, 2013 - 2:47pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-announces-opening-of-hemet-office%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Rep. Ruiz Joins House in Passing Violence Against Women Act</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-joins-house-in-passing-violence-against-women-act</link>
    <description>February 28, 2013WASHINGTON, DC&amp;nbsp;--- U.S. Representative Raul Ruiz, M.D. (D-Palm Desert) today voted in favor of the bipartisan Senate-passed version of the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA). The bill, which passed the House by a margin of&amp;nbsp;286-138, will now go to the President&amp;rsquo;s desk for signature. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;No woman should ever have to suffer domestic abuse,&amp;rdquo; said Rep. Ruiz. &amp;ldquo;The passage of this critical legislation is a victory for women in the 36th&amp;nbsp;District and across the country, and I was proud to stand with a bipartisan majority of my colleagues to reauthorize this landmark law. The bill we passed today will ensure that all victims of domestic and sexual abuse, regardless of their background, are given the protections they deserve and have access to the resources they need to seek justice.&amp;rdquo;In addition to voting in support of the bipartisan Senate-passed version of VAWA today, Rep. Ruiz joined the House in voting down a weaker House GOP version of the bill that excluded protections for Native American, immigrant, and LGBT women.&amp;nbsp;The reauthorization bill the House passed provides stronger protections for all women and&amp;nbsp;strengthens the ability of the Federal Government, the States, law enforcement, and service providers to combat domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.&amp;nbsp;Yesterday, during his first speech on the House floor as a U.S. Representative, Rep. Ruiz urged passage of a strong, comprehensive version of VAWA and spoke out against the weaker House GOP version of the bill. A clip of that video is available&amp;nbsp;here&amp;nbsp;and the remarks as prepared for delivery are below.###&amp;nbsp;STATEMENT OF THE HONORABLE RAUL RUIZFLOOR STATEMENTS.47&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013&amp;nbsp;Thank You Mr. Speaker.I would like to thank the Senate for working in a bipartisan manner to pass the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act. However, the House Republican version of the bill fails to protect all women, including Native American women, immigrant women and the LGBT community.I rise today in strong opposition to the House Republican version of the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act.&amp;nbsp; As an ER doctor I have seen firsthand the beaten and bruised bodies of women and the invisible scars left on the victim, her family and community.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Native American women in my district and across the country endure an epidemic of domestic violence and in most cases the abusers are not members of the tribe. Tribes must have the right to protect their daughters, sisters and mothers from violence.&amp;nbsp;We must work to make sure that all women are protected from domestic violence.I urge all of my colleagues to join me in opposition to the House Republican version of this legislation and I look forward to the passage of the bipartisan Senate version of this legislation. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, February 28, 2013 - 3:40am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-joins-house-in-passing-violence-against-women-act%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Rep. Ruiz Votes to Block Congressional Pay Raise</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-votes-to-block-congressional-pay-raise</link>
    <description>&amp;nbsp;Washington, DC&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; U.S. Representative Raul Ruiz, M.D. (D-Palm Desert) today voted for H.R. 273 to overturn an automatic pay raise for Members of Congress and continue the current federal government pay freeze. This legislation is estimated to save U.S. taxpayers $11 billion.&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;During a time when many families in the 36th&amp;nbsp;District are struggling to make ends meet and our country is facing a $17 trillion national debt and the threat of deep, across-the-board cuts to defense and health care programs, the last thing Members of Congress should be doing is giving themselves a taxpayer-funded pay raise,&amp;rdquo; said Rep. Ruiz. &amp;ldquo;It is time for Congress to show the American people we are serious about eliminating unnecessary spending, and that begins with personal accountability and ending wasteful pay raises for ourselves.&amp;rdquo;H.R. 273 passed the House by a margin of 261 to 154, with 43 Democrats, including Rep. Ruiz, voting in support.###</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, February 15, 2013 - 1:56pm</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-votes-to-block-congressional-pay-raise%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Rep. Ruiz Cosponsors Violence Against Women Act, Urges House to Take Up Senate-Passed Reauthorization  </title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-cosponsors-violence-against-women-act-urges-house-to-take-up</link>
    <description>&amp;nbsp;Washington, D.C.&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; U.S. Representative Raul Ruiz, M.D. (D-Palm Desert) today cosponsored H.R. 11, the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) and called upon House leadership to quickly bring the bipartisan Senate-passed version of the bill to the floor for a vote. Earlier this week the Senate passed the VAWA Reauthorization by a vote of 78 to 22.&amp;ldquo;We cannot continue to delay the passage of this critical legislation,&amp;rdquo; said Rep. Ruiz. &amp;ldquo;This bill will help protect victims of domestic violence and provide our local communities and law enforcement agencies with the resources they need to hold perpetrators accountable. No woman should have to live in fear of domestic abuse or sexual violence. This is an issue that deserves bipartisan action now.&amp;rdquo;The bipartisan Senate-passed VAWA Reauthorization strengthens the ability of the Federal Government, the States, law enforcement, and service providers to combat domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.&amp;nbsp;The legislation also includes stronger protections for tribal members, immigrants, and members of the LGBT community.###</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, February 14, 2013 - 11:32am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-cosponsors-violence-against-women-act-urges-house-to-take-up%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title> Rep. Ruiz Statement on the President’s State of the Union Address</title>
    <link>http://ruiz.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-statement-on-the-president-s-state-of-the-union-address</link>
    <description>&amp;nbsp;Washington, DC&amp;nbsp;--- U.S. Representative Raul Ruiz, M.D. (D-Palm Desert) tonight released the following statement regarding the President&amp;rsquo;s State of the Union address:&amp;ldquo;In his State of the Union address tonight, the President emphasized a plan to strengthen our middle class, accelerate economic growth and job creation, and prepare future generations of American workers to compete in the global economy. I agree with the President that we must make our nation a magnet for new jobs and create incentives for companies to hire and invest in American workers. I also agree that we must give every student in our nation the opportunity to succeed by expanding opportunities for a high-quality, affordable education. As the President said in his speech tonight, the American people expect us to put the nation&amp;rsquo;s interests before the interests of our political parties. I will continue to work with my colleagues to move our country forward in a bipartisan way and meet the challenges at hand.&amp;rdquo;###</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, February 13, 2013 - 10:55am</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>43</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ruiz.house.gov/%3Ca%20href%3D%22/media-center/press-releases/rep-ruiz-statement-on-the-president-s-state-of-the-union-address%22%3Eview%3C/a%3E</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
